Personal info Mr Takudzwa Mawarire



- No. 10 Bryden Rd, Mount Pleasant, Harare, Zimbabwe
- **** +263779960053
- tkmawarire@live.com
- https://takudzwa.azurewebsites.net
- Zimbabwean
- 14/07/1992
- Married

Profile

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | GIS EXPERT

I combine my advanced knowledge, experience and skills with technology in order to develop professional and innovative applications.

I follow OAUTH, REST and SOLID software engineering principles. I am also a fan of BDD and Agile methodologies.

By following the best practices, I produce "clean code" which is comprehensive, easy to read, debug and maintain.

An innovator of next-generation solutions, systems and applications giving companies a competitive edge and producing outstanding results for customers.

I have a keen eye for great user interfaces and have a unique approach to problemsolving. I never stop learning.

Work experience

10/2018 - present

Implementation & Support Developer

Sybrin (ZW), Harare, Zimbabwe

Sybrin is an industry leading company in the realms of **Banking**, **Financial Services & Customer Acquisition** in Africa.I am currently serving as an implementation and support developer. My primary work includes:

- Upgrade existing systems to Sybrin Enterprise Studio (ASP.NET Core, Angular 7, Redis, Dapper, and MSSQL).
- Design and collaborate with the team on change requests and new projects.
- Implement Change Requests and New Projects.
- Build in-house systems to improve day to day work-flows (Angular 7, ASP.NET Core, SQL Server)
- Troubleshoot errors at existing customers (Sybrin Applications :- C# & SQL Server (TSQL)).
- Improve efficiency of current systems.
- Testing & Documenting projects (ASP.NET Core, C#, Angular 7)

To date, I had the opportunity to be part in the development of solutions for various clients that include BancABC BW, Standard Bank ZW, Akribos Capital & First Capital Bank (Barclays ZW)

08/2014 - 09/2018

Solutions Developer & GIS Expert

Integral Edge Systems Design, Harare, Zimbabwe

I served as a Solutions Developer & GIS Expert at the company. I started out as an intern software developer & GIS consultant, while I was also studying. I had the opportunity to be part in the development of solutions for various clients that include UNICEF, The Netherlands Development Organization (SNV) & the Government of Zimbabwe.

- Led solutions engineering that involved process automation and functionality enhancement. Replaced time-consuming, error-prone manual processes with elegant, automated solutions.
- Developed and enhanced programs using JavaScript, C#, contributing to solutions that streamlined processes, increased accuracy and lowered costs.
- · Presenting ideas for system improvements
- Writing the program code (client side and back-end)
- Implementing complex GIS modeling algorithms in code.
- Testing the product in controlled, real situations before going live
- · Preparation of training manuals for users
- Maintaining the systems once they are up and running

Work experience

06/2016 - 08/2016

GIS Developer

GISKONSULT, Gweru, Zimbabwe

GISKonsult PIc is a Division of Greatop Investments Pvt. Ltd which is based in Gweru, Zimbabwe. I was contracted to develop a Custom Web Based Municipal GIS for the city of Gweru based on a prototype I had developed for my final year project.

- Gather and refine specifications and requirements based on technical needs
- Write well designed, testable, efficient code by using best software development practices
- Create user interfaces and back-end using standard ASP.NET MVC 5 practices
- Design and develop a robust geo database on SQL Server 2014
- Create and maintain software documentation

Education

06/2011 - 11/2016

B.Sc. Honours in Surveying & Geomatics

Midlands State University, Gweru, Zimbabwe

Studying surveying & geomatics was not by **choice**, but toward the end, I found a **passion (GIS & Software Development).** I have to face life with a newly found passion. Passion is the energy that keeps me going, that keeps me filled with meaning, and happiness, and excitement, and anticipation.

Graded: Upper Second (2.1)

Achievements

Development of a Web based Service Fault Reporting GIS for use by the local municipality (Gweru City Council).

Presentations

Survey Institute of Zimbabwe Annual General Meeting 2016 Victoria Falls : Web Based Service Fault Reporting GIS.

Skills

Software & Web Development		GIS	
C# ASP.NET Framework Angular 7 Node.js SQL Server 2008 & Up Postgres Xamarin .Net React.js Javascript TypeScript		Cartography Spatial Analysis Geo Database Design & Management GIS Development ArcGIS QGIS AutoCAD Map/ Civil 3D Spatial Modeling	